You said we were starting morning training
today, so I show up, and what do I find?
（佑真(ゆうま)）
今日から朝練っつうから
何やんのかと思えば…
（佑真）ワカメ漁？
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）佑真　サボるなよ！
We're seaweed harvesting?!
Yuma, no slacking off!
I-I can't take it!
（蛍(けい)）も… もうダメです
（小関(おぜき)）三ツ橋(みつはし)　しっかりし…
（吐く音）
Mitsuhashi, get a hold of—
Hey, man, keep our oceans clean.
（千比路(ちひろ)）おいおい 海を汚すなよ
Come on, guys. Hiring this
boat cost money, remember.
（桐仁(きりひと)）頼みますよ　タダで 船
出してもらってるわけじゃないんで
Slave driver.
鬼かよ…
Bout 4
"Dachi High's Fifth Member"
Okay, then. Let's get started.
（桐仁）
そろそろ始めましょうか
Ow... This is hard.
難しいな これ
There was a French artist...
（桐仁）フランスの芸術家…
（小関）うん？
...by the name of Jean Cocteau
who called sumo "the art of balance."
（桐仁）かのジャン･コクトーは
相撲を“バランスの芸術”と称した
The basic idea of sumo is to
knock your opponent off balance.
相撲ってのは 要するに
バランスの崩し合いなんです
I get it now.
（火ノ丸）なるほどな
（桐仁）うん？
This is going to strengthen
the muscles we use for balance.
バランスを取るのに必要な筋肉が…
（しこを踏む音）
より鍛えられるってわけじゃ
Correct.
（桐仁）そういうこと
（千比路）ナハハハッ！
I knew that was your reason
for this boat trip all along!
俺は分かってたぜ　お前の意図を
And the seaweed has something
to do with it too, doesn't it?
そして
ワカメにも何か秘密があるんだな？
You can grab the seaweed like this, is that it?
だから こうして
ワカメをガッとつかむ感じがよ
Like grabbing a mawashi belt?
廻(まわ)しをつかむ感じに似てるとか
そんな感じだろう？
The seaweed is not part of the training.
ワカメは関係ないです
Huh? Oh...
あっ…　あっ そう
（佑真）
アアッ…　朝っぱらから疲れたぜ
It's still morning, but I'm already beat.
I'll just take a nice long nap during class.
（千比路）
こりゃ授業中 よく眠れそうだ
You still remember that day, don't you?
（火ノ丸）
あんときのことを覚えとるか？
Oh, you were in the arena today, Kirihito?
（火ノ丸）
なんじゃ 桐仁　会場 来とったんか
（桐仁）試合は見れなかったけどな
I didn't see you compete, though.
You drop out way too quickly.
お前(めえ)が あんまり早く
負けちまうもんだからよ
（火ノ丸）
ウヘヘッ…　そりゃ すまんな
Sorry about that.
Something wrong, Kirihito?
（火ノ丸）どうした？　桐仁
（桐仁）お前さ…
Hey...
Do you like sumo?
相撲 楽しいか？
あ… 当たり前じゃろうが！
Of course I do!
I like it because I can use my yokozuna-style
sumo to win! That's what makes it fun!
ワシの好きな この相撲で—
横綱相撲で勝つからこそ
楽しいんじゃ！
You haven't won at all since
you started middle school.
（桐仁）中学になってから
全然 勝ててねえじゃん
（火ノ丸）ンンッ…
（桐仁）それでも楽しいのか？
Are you sure it's still fun?
Yokozuna-style sumo is all well and good,
横綱相撲も いいけどさ
but isn't there a more practical way?
もっと身の丈に合った道が
あるんじゃねえのか？
Just because you work hard, it doesn't
mean you'll be successful, Hinomaru.
努力すれば 必ず報われるとは
限らねえんだぜ 火ノ丸
Master Yamatokuni told me
basically the same thing.
似たようなことを
大和国(やまとくに)親方にも言われたのぅ
Master Yamatokuni? In your first year
at middle school, you mean?
（桐仁）大和国に？
えっと…　中１のときか？
Yeah.
（火ノ丸）そうじゃ
大横綱じきじきに
土俵入りの指導を受けてな
I got a direct lesson
from that master yokozuna.
Okay. Now, show me some of your moves.
（大和国）よし　では
一連の動きを通しでやってみようか
（火ノ丸）はい！
Yes, sir!
Isn't he last year's "young boy yokozuna"?
（記者）あれが前年度の少年横綱？
He's pretty small. Maybe
he hasn't grown since last year.
（記者）小さいな　去年と
あまり変わってないんじゃないか？
He hasn't been performing this year,
probably due to his size.
（記者）案の定
中学ではロクに勝てとらんらしい
You three...
（大和国）
君たち　話題は選びたまえよ
Choose your words better.
ウヘヘッ…　ワシは別に…
I don't mind.
Even so...
（大和国）とはいえ…
（火ノ丸）うん？
Isn't it foolhardy to attack head-on
with your diminutive stature?
（大和国）なぜ君は その体で
無謀な真っ向勝負を続けるのかね？
Master Yamatokuni, you yourself met
opponents head-on during your career.
大和国親方も 現役時代は
真っ向勝負が信条じゃったろう
That is how I live.
それが 私の生き方だからだ
Well, that goes for me, too.
まあ そういうことじゃ
I will wear another yokozuna belt.
ワシは必ず
この身に また“横綱”を巻く
笑いたきゃ笑え
If you want to laugh at me, go ahead!
Practice for three years from now.
３年先の稽古をしなさい
Three years from now?
３年先の稽古？
Then, you can show me
そのときに見せてもらうとしよう
君の生き方をね
how you have chosen to live.
I haven't changed my mind one bit.
今もワシの考えは変わってはおらん
ただのバカげた意地じゃ
'Cause I'm pigheaded.
You sure are, but it works for you.
ああ　お前は それでいい
I prepared for this eventuality.
そのために 俺は準備してきたんだ
Oh, yeah. I was curious,
so I did some research
（千比路）
そういや ちょっと興味があって
調べてみたんだけどよ
on how to get into professional sumo.
大相撲って
どうやったら入れるんだろうって
Are you setting your sights
on becoming a sekitori?
（蛍）
まさか 関取 目指すんですか？
My goal is to be a mixed martial artist.
俺のゴールは あくまで“総合”だ
いいか？　大相撲には
まず 新弟子検査ってのがあってな
Listen to this: "To become a pro, sumo wrestlers
must pass a physical entrance exam.
The minimum height requirement is 167 cm."
身長167センチ以下のヤツは
失格なんだと
（蛍）えっ？　…てことは
（小関）そうなんだ
But that means...
Yeah. No matter how hard he trains,
he can't make it into the pro league.
あいつが どれだけ
死にものぐるいで頑張っても—
プロには なれない
Is he pushing himself this hard
just because he likes sumo?
ただ相撲が好きってだけで—
あそこまで
がむしゃらになれるもんなのか？
Where on earth does he get his motivation?
あいつのモチベーションって
一体 どこにあるんだ？
I've laid out individual
training regimes for you all.
（桐仁）新しく
個人メニューを作ってきました
I'd like you all to follow them to the letter.
今日から各自
これに沿って やってください
Individual training regimes?
（小関）個人メニューか…
Um...
（蛍）あの…
（桐仁）うん？
You're taking part in the tournaments too,
aren't you, Tsuji-san?
大会では
辻(つじ)さんも試合に出るんですよね？
Shouldn't you be focusing
on your own training?
それなら 自分の練習にも
時間を充てたほうが…
俺は 試合には出ない
I won't be competing in any bouts.
Are you sure you want a beginner
like me on the team?
素人の僕が
レギュラーでいいんですか？
I'm more than happy to do it, but...
それはそれで うれしいですけど…
You've done sumo before, haven't you?
お前　経験者だろう？
団体戦で 少しでも
勝率を上げるってんなら—
If we want to maximize our chances of
winning, shouldn't you be competing, too?
出るべきじゃねえのか？
大体 実力の分かんねえヤツから
指図されたくねえし
Also, I don't like being ordered around by
someone who might not even be any good.
What a pain.
（桐仁）面倒くせえな
（佑真）ああ！？
What?!
I'll show you by getting our rookie,
Mitsuhashi, to beat the lot of you.
だったら その素人の三ツ橋で
あんたら全員に勝ってみせるよ
（佑真たち）うん？
（蛍）なな… 何言ってるんですか
Wh-Wh-What are you saying?!
That's not what I meant at all!
僕が言いたいのは
そういうことじゃなくて…
Don't worry. Just do what I tell you.
いいから
俺の言うとおりにやってみて
This guy's kinda arrogant, isn't he?
（千比路）
ちょっと感じ悪いな
あいつ
ナメやがって…
面白(おもしれ)えじゃねえか
He's making fun of us.
I'm going to enjoy this.
（佑真）ああ？
（蛍）ヒイッ！
ムリムリ　絶対ムリだよ…
Not happening! I can't do this!
Spirit!
（千比路）はっきよい！
（佑真）ンッ…
Take this! And this! And that!
グッ…　手を… 手だけを見るんだ
His hands. Watch his hands!
There!
そこだ！
No way...
（蛍）ウソ…
Nice work, Kei.
やるのぅ 蛍
He was waiting until
Yuma-san's feet were square on.
（小関）佑真さんの
両足がそろったところを狙われた
Dammit! What happened?!
（佑真）ちくしょう なんでだ！
（桐仁）解説いる？
Shall I explain?
Your weakness is your hand slaps.
（桐仁）
あんたの突きは 手打ちなんだよ
You put all of your strength into your
upper body, and your legs don't keep up.
上半身だけに力が入って
足がついてこない
So simply moving out of the way
puts you off balance.
だから 退(ひ)けば簡単に落ちるのさ
What?!
そんな…
Your normal sparring partner
is partly to blame.
ふだんの稽古の相手も
悪いんだよな
That idiot doesn't know how to pull away.
あのバカは
退くことを知らないから
He can't object when he's on the ground.
実際に負かされちゃ
ぐうの音も出ねえわな
Now, what lesson do you
have for me, professor?
さて 俺には
何を見せてくれるのかね？　ハカセ
"Professor"?
ハカセ？
Mitsuhashi.
（桐仁）三ツ橋
（蛍）あっ…
He beat Yuma-san, but Kunisaki's
a national wrestling champion.
佑真さんには勝ったけど
國崎(くにさき)はレスリング日本一だぞ
What could his weakness be?
（小関）隙なんて そうそう…
（佑真）はっきよい！
Spirit!
A-An inside ankle sweep?
（小関）け… 蹴手繰(けたぐ)り！
（千比路）ンンッ…
（桐仁）解説いる？
Shall I explain?
Yeah. If you would.
ああ　要るね
Your footwork isn't where it needs to be.
あんたは足さばきが まだまだだね
踏み込む際に 若干 足が浮く
When you take a step, your foot isn't flat.
Work on pointing your toes outward and
shuffling your whole sole when you move.
外股で 足裏全体を使う すり足を
身に着けないとダメだよ
はい…
Yes, prof.
Hey, Ozeki.
おい 小関　負けたら承知しねえぞ
You'd better not lose.
（小関）ンンッ…　は… はい
O-Okay.
Spirit!
（火ノ丸）はっきよい！
（蛍）ンッ…
A leg grab?
（小関）足取り！
But I can push back.
でも このくらいなら耐えられ…
No, not like that. Closer to the ankle.
違う違う　もっと足首のほう！
Okay!
はい！　グ〜ッ…
グワッ！　アッ…
ほう…
Wow.
やった！
I did it!
そんな…　どうして？
But... how?
President, your legs and loins are strong,
（桐仁）部長は足腰は強いけど
上半身 弱いよね
but your upper body is weak, correct?
You didn't push him hard enough,
so you let him get in close.
前さばきに力がないから
今も あっさり懐を許した
This jerk knows everything about us...
あの野郎…
俺らのことを こんなに…
I get it. I see what you're saying.
なるほどな
お前の言いたいことは分かったぜ
So basically,
つまりは こうだ
対戦相手の情報を収集し
弱点を突いて勝つ
one needs to research their opponents and
take advantage of their weaknesses to win.
俺たちに足りないのは そう…
But we're lacking in that department...
The brains!
知略！
Say something!
何か言えよ！
No one who competes at national level
has weaknesses as obvious as yours.
（桐仁）
全国上位には あんたらのように
分かりやすい弱点なんてないですよ
And why would they?
当然だ
They're experienced,
well-rounded sumo wrestlers.
あんたらとは力士としての年季が…
完成度が違う
A team of beginners with only
a few months of slapdash training
この素人集団が 今のまま—
やみくもに
数か月 稽古したところで—
would struggle to pass
the Prefectural prelims.
県予選突破も難しいでしょうね
そのために 俺がいる
And that's why you have me.
What I just showed you with the
help of Mitsuhashi aren't weaknesses.
今 俺が 三ツ橋を使って見せたのは
弱点じゃない　伸びしろだ
They are areas to improve.
With the time we have left,
（桐仁）現状でも
そこそこ使えてる各自の武器を—
we'll hone the weapons each
of you possess to a keen edge.
残された期間 徹底的に磨き上げる
Even if you aren't well-rounded,
you only need one killer move.
力士としては不完全でも
１つでいい　全国にも負けない—
Become specalist sumo wrestlers with one
move that can cut it in the national level.
研ぎ澄まされた一芸を持った
異能力士になるんだ
Specialist sumo wrestlers...
異能力士…
Now, Hinomaru...
（桐仁）さて 火ノ丸
（火ノ丸）うん？
I need to show you what you can improve.
お前にも
その伸びしろを示してやらないとな
Come with me.
来いよ　大将戦を始めよう
Let's begin our bout.
線は細いが
なかなか鍛えてんじゃん
He's slim, but he definitely works out.
結局 出るんだ？
So he is competing?
I think they were in the same
elementary school sumo club.
確か 小学校の相撲クラブで
一緒だったんだっけ…
Hey, Hinomaru. Is Tsuji good?
どうなんだ？　潮(うしお)　辻の実力
（小関）あっ…
（佑真）仲いいんじゃねえのかよ…
I thought they were friends.
いいんじゃな？　桐仁
Are you sure, Kirihito?
I won't hold back in the ring.
土俵に上がったら
手加減はできんぞ
Maybe I don't make myself clear at times,
but you, on the other hand, talk too much.
俺が ひと言足りねえなら
お前は ひと言 余計だ
何さまのつもりだ？
Who do you think you are? You need
to leave that attitude outside of the ring.
そういうくだらねえのは
土俵の外に捨ててこい
Just so you know,
I'm using a leaf out of your book.
先に言っとくが
立ち合い 変化はしねえ
I'll attack you head-on.
真っ向勝負だ
Otherwise, you won't get
the point I'm trying to make.
でないと
伝えたいことが伝わらねえからな
あ… あれは—
Th-That's...
...a spider stance!
平蜘蛛型(ひらぐもがた)仕切り！
Can he even get up from a stance that low?
あんな低い姿勢で立てんのか？
Fine by me.
上等
（ぶつかり合う音）
（千比路）速(はえ)え！
He's fast!
He forced Hinomaru to make low contact
超低空のぶちかましで突き上げて
懐に…
and sealed off his charge!
出足の難しい あの仕切りを…
No way... How's he doing
so well against Hinomaru-san?
ウソだろう？　火ノ丸さんを相手に
うらぁ！
He got him by the throat to force him off!
喉輪(のどわ)で 強引に離した！
Those are some heavy blows.
重てえ…
これが お前の目指した横綱相撲か
Is this the yokozuna-style sumo
you've been striving for?
But don't forget, Hinomaru:
でもな 火ノ丸
横綱相撲ってのは—
You can't call it yokozuna-style
sumo unless you win!
勝って初めて そう呼ばれるんだ！
He grabbed his arm to switch places!
手繰って 体を入れ替えた！
This guy's got some crazy technique!
あんにゃろう…
相当なテクニシャンだぜ
That's the right-handed
belt grip Ushio uses!
これは… 右四つ　潮の型だ
What do you think you're doing?
どういうつもりじゃ？　てめえ
Are you inviting me to do it?
（火ノ丸）誘っとるんか？
（桐仁）ハァハァ…
（火ノ丸）お望みどおり
食らわせてやるよ ワシの３年！
Have it your way. I'll do it!
Here comes three years' training!
He's going for it.
（佑真）出るぞ
（小関）潮の最大火力
Ushio's most powerful move!
A technique that combines
a throw with a turn!
（火ノ丸）
投げと ひねりの合わせ技…
Hundred demon takedown!
Hundred
Demon
Take
Down
Just because you work hard,
it doesn't mean you'll be successful.
努力すれば
必ず報われるとは限らねえんだぜ
今でも後悔している
I still regret saying it.
What I just said to him...
今のあいつに…
誰よりも努力してるあいつに…
He works much harder than anyone else,
and that's all I can say to him?!
こんなクソみてえなことしか
言えねえのか 俺は
もう言わねえ
考えてきたんだ 報われる方法を
I won't say it ever again.
I've come up with a way
you can be successful.
I won't let your hard work go to waste!
お前の努力を
ムダになんかさせねえ！
They're both doing the
hundred demon takedown!
百鬼薙(ひゃっきな)ぎの打ち合い！
I'll take your sumo that
couldn't defeat Kusanagi
“草薙(くさなぎ)”に
通用しなかったお前の相撲を—
and make it a thing of the past!
今 この手で 過去のものにする！
He's crazy! Ushio's way too strong!
ムチャだ！
パワーは 潮のほうが上だ
受け取れ 火ノ丸
これが お前の可能性だ！
Take this, Hinomaru!
This is your potential!
投げと ひねりと もう一手…
A throw, a turn, and a little something extra!
A triple combo technique!
（桐仁）３つの合わせ技！
Damn. It's been a while since
I was left staring at the ceiling.
くそ…　久々に天井 見上げたぜ
I take it... you don't need me... to explain.
解説は… 要らねえな　ハァ…
It's more than a simple throw...
and turn... It's three attacks... in one.
投げと ひねりの
合わせ技を超える３点同時攻撃—
That's... the one opportunity...
you've got left.
それこそが
お前に残された唯一の活路
つまり 新必殺技の修得？
So you're giving him
a decisive new technique?
A triple combo does sound
stronger than a double combo.
確かに
２つより３つのが強力だわな
ウヘヘッ…
こいつは危険な賭けじゃな
That move's a real risk, though.
Huh? Why?
（千比路）えっ？　なんで？
（小関）そりゃそうだよ
Of course it is.
２つでも合わせるのは至難の業
それを３つだ
It's difficult enough combining two moves.
But we're talking about three.
And there's no coming back from it.
しかも 今のは捨て身の技
しくじれば 次の手はないんだ
If it doesn't work,
you're out of options.
So his final trump card is a huge gamble?
最後の切り札が
そんなバクチみてえな技かよ
Are you sure about this, Ushio?
いいのか？　潮
Thanks, Kirihito.
ありがとうよ 桐仁
（桐仁）ハァハァ…
（火ノ丸）その賭け 乗ったぜ
I'll take that gamble.
俺も
かつては お前の相撲を否定した
I once rejected your sumo,
but truth is, I want to see more of it.
でも 本当は見てえんだ
I want to see you charge at
towering titans and floor them.
（桐仁）でっけえヤツを
真っ向勝負で ぶっ倒す…
That will be your own style of
yokozuna sumo: "Hinomaru sumo."
お前だけの横綱相撲
“火ノ丸相撲”をな
"Hinomaru sumo."
（小関）火ノ丸相撲…
Okay, I'll leave the rest of you to tidy up.
（桐仁）じゃ ここからは
個人メニューの時間ってことで…
つうわけで
ホタルのスタメン落ちは決定だな
I guess this means you'll be
sitting on the bench, Hotaru.
That... That was incredible!
す… すごいですよ！
He's a coach, and a really
strong sumo wrestler, too!
監督もできて
選手としても あんなに強い
Dachi High might just become
the best sumo school in Japan!
ダチ高
ホントに日本一になっちゃうかも
Oh, his glasses.
あっ メガネ　辻さ〜ん！
Tsuji-san!
ハハハッ！
俺と火ノ丸とハカセで３勝
Me, Hinomaru, and the prof
is three guaranteed wins!
That's how we'll breeze through
the group competitions!
やっと
団体戦の勝ち星計算ができるぜ
Hey, what about me?
（佑真）おい 俺は？
Sorry to dampen the mood, but listen.
（火ノ丸）浮かれとるとこ
すまんが 聞いとくれ
（火ノ丸）桐仁は
団体戦のメンバーには なれん
Kirihito can't compete
in group competitions.
You've discovered... my secret.
まあ そういうことだ…
His lungs are weak.
（火ノ丸）もともと肺が弱くてな
相撲は 僅か数秒の勝負じゃが
その数秒が すさまじい
Sumo bouts only last a few seconds,
but they're super intense.
He can maybe last twenty seconds.
（火ノ丸）もって20秒
（３人）あっ…
Kirihito is a sumo wrestler who
can only fight for twenty seconds.
桐仁は
20秒しか戦えない力士なんじゃ
N-No...
そ… そんな…
If I fight longer than twenty seconds...
（桐仁）20秒を超えるとな…
溺れるんだ
I drown.
There's no way I could
last an entire tournament...
１日に何試合もある学生相撲の大会
とても戦い抜くことはできねえ
where they... contest several bouts a day.
自分の運命を呪ったよ
I've cursed my fate...
and lost the will to continue.
そのうち 続ける意義も失って
一度は相撲をやめた
I even went as far as quitting sumo.
（蛍）アア…
（桐仁）でも 見ちまったんだよな
But then... I saw something.
An idiot, mocked by fate like I am,
（桐仁）俺と同じように
運命に翻弄されながらも—
who carried on fighting regardless.
抗(あらが)い続けるバカ野郎を
I'm pathetic.
自分が情けねえ
I like sumo, so what else is there to it?
“相撲が好き”
それ以外に 何が要るんだってな
That's why you became a coach?
だから 監督の道を…
Yeah.
ああ
せめて あいつの力になりたくてな
I want to help him succeed.
Then, it's even more important!
だったら なおさらです
How can someone who's not even
standing at the starting line compete?
スタートラインにすら
立てていない僕が—
試合に出るわけにはいきません
いいや　お前は もう力士だよ
No. You're a sumo wrestler now.
知ってるぞ　練習のあと—
I know what you've been
doing after practice.
１人で何やってんのか
あ… あれは 練習の時間だけじゃ
とても回数こなせないから…
I-I'm just not able to do it
enough times during practice.
Dachi High's fifth member...
ダチ高の５人目は
お前だぜ　三ツ橋
is you, Mitsuhashi.
That's gotta be tough.
（千比路）つれえだろうな あいつ
Being unable to do sumo
because your body's too weak.
体が弱いって理由で
相撲ができないなんて…
Hinomaru's in the same boat.
（佑真）
それを言うなら火ノ丸もじゃねえか
You can't be a pro at your height, right?
お前　その身長じゃ
プロには なれねえんだろう？
Yuma-san!
佑真さん！
なのに なんで そこまで
がむしゃらになれるんだ？
If you already know that,
why do you train so hard?
I'll tell you why.
（桐仁）あるんです
He doesn't meet the pro league requirements,
but there is a way he can join it.
新弟子基準に満たない火ノ丸が
堂々とプロ入りできる方法が
（佑真）なに？
What?
The inter-high individual champion
is named the "high school yokozuna"
インターハイ 個人戦優勝者は
高校横綱と呼ばれ—
and is invited to participate in the
All-Japan National Championships.
その年の全日本選手権への
出場権も獲得できる
全日本選手権？
The All-Japan National Championships?
It's a tourney for amateur sumo wrestlers,
including college students and working adults.
大学生 社会人を含めた
アマチュア日本一を決める大会だよ
If you win it, you receive preference
and enter the Makushita division.
そこで優勝すれば
幕下付出(まくしたつけだし)の資格が与えられるんだ
Receive preference?
“付出(つけだし)”って何だ？
Pro sumo has a preferential
system for incoming members.
プロ入りの際の優遇制度だね
Normally, you'd start off unranked,
but the champion skips several divisions,
Yokozuna
Ozeki
Sekiwake
Komusubi
Maegashira
Juryo
Makushita
Sandanme
Jonidan
Jonokuchi
Sanyaku
Makuuchi
(42 Wrestlers)
Juryo (28 Wrestlers)
Sekitori
Makushita
and below
通常 前相撲から
始めるところを—
一気に飛ばして—
and debuts in the Makushita division.
幕下から
デビューできるんだ
うん？　どっちにしても
身長の件は解決してなくねえ？
I don't see how that satisfies
the height requirement.
Uh, yeah, I was wondering that, too.
俺も そう思うんだけど…
Captain, did you read the rule in full?
（桐仁）部長
規定 最後まで読みましたか？
Amateur sumo wrestlers given preference
do not need to pass any physical exams.
（桐仁）“付出資格を
有するアマチュア力士は—”
“プロ入りの際
体格は不問とする”
（千比路）えっ？
（小関）そうだったのか
I see!
To go down that route, Hinomaru must
become the high school yokozuna.
そのためにも まず—
火ノ丸は 高校横綱に
ならなきゃいけないんです
Please, allow me to be your coach.
お願いします
俺に監督をやらせてください
I wish to help Hinomaru realize his dream!
火ノ丸の夢を支えてやりたいんです
Yamatokuni
Stable
（久世(くぜ)）練習とはいえ
他校の選手と試合をしました
Even though it was only practice, I competed
in a bout with someone from another school.
父さんの意に
反することと知りながら…
I knew it was contrary
to your wishes, Father.
申し訳ありません
Please forgive me.
How did it feel?
（大和国）どんな気分だった？
I was reminded of how much I love sumo.
改めて思いました
僕は相撲が好きです
There are other opponents competing in high
school sumo that make me feel the same way.
そう思わせてくれる相手が
高校相撲には まだまだいます
それら全てに打ち勝ち
高校相撲の頂点に立ったのち—
I want to defeat them all, become
the top high school sumo wrestler,
and join the professional ranks.
角界に入ります
大和国の息子という誇りを胸に
I will wear my status as the son
of Yamatokuni like a badge of honor.
That is how I shall live.
それが 僕の生き方です
This is the first time you've
expressed your own desires.
（大和国）
初めて自分の意思を見せたな
（久世）あっ…
（大和国）好きに生きろ
Live as you see fit.
Yes, sir.
はい
By the way, who was it that
excited such passion in you?
ところで
お前に火をつけた その相手—
一体 誰なんだ？
Ushio Hinomaru-kun.
（久世）潮火ノ丸君です
火ノ丸…
Hinomaru...
I see... So he's been training
hard for the last three years...
そうか…
３年先の稽古を重ねてきたんだな
You can stop bowing now, Tsuji.
I understand how much this means to you.
顔を上げてくれ 辻
お前の覚悟は よく分かった
Kuze isn't the only
heavyweight you must defeat.
倒すべき相手は
久世だけじゃありません
Across the country, there are others
who bear national treasure monikers.
全国には “国宝”と
呼ばれる選手が ほかにもいます
Ishigami High School's
technically-gifted Sada Mizuki.
石神(いしがみ)高校の業師
沙田美月(さだみづき)
Kanazawa Kita High School's giant,
Hikage Tenma.
金沢北(かなざわきた)高校の巨人
日景典馬(ひかげてんま)
And...
そして 鳥取白楼(とっとりはくろう)—
Tottori Hakuo's Tennoji Shido,
the strongest high school yokozuna in history.
史上最強の高校横綱
天王寺獅童(てんのうじしどう)
There's that many?
（佑真）そんなにいんのかよ…
（千比路）ワクワクすんなぁ！
This is getting pretty exciting!
Cutting them all down to size
and wearing the belt of a yokozuna...
そいつら全員 刈り取って
横綱を腰に巻く
That was my goal.
それが ワシの目標じゃった
“じゃった”？
"Was"?
I have a bigger goal now.
今は もっとでかい目標がある
We're going to be the best team in Japan!
ワシら全員で
日本一になることじゃ！
Who, us?
全員で…
Tsuji...
（小関）辻…
（桐仁）はい
Yes?
I'd like to make a formal request.
正式にお願いしたい
ダチ高相撲部の監督に就任してくれ
Please become the coach of
the Dachi High sumo club!
We've been relying on
Ushio to handle everything.
今までは全部 潮に頼りきりだった
でも それじゃダメなんだ
But that's not good enough!
Ushio being the best
in Japan won't satisfy us.
潮に日本一にしてもらうんじゃない
We're all going to be the best in Japan!
俺たち みんなで
ダチ高を日本一にするんだ
そのために協力してほしい
Please help us to achieve that aim!
部長…
Captain...
You'd best be prepared for hell
starting tomorrow.
あしたから覚悟してくださいね
B-Bring it on.
（佑真）の… 望むところだ
（蛍）頑張ります！
I'll do my best!
Then, we'll be harvesting seaweed again.
（桐仁）
では あしたも 朝からワカメ漁です
（蛍）ええっ！
思い出したら また吐き気が…
Just remembering it makes me want to...
（千比路）
えっ？　土俵で吐くなよ ホタル！
Don't hurl in the ring, Hotaru!
This isn't chankonabe stew.
（佑真）ちゃんこっつうか
ただのワカメ汁じゃねえか
It's just seaweed soup.
Eating as a team makes
everything taste great!
（火ノ丸）
みんなで食うと うまいのぅ！
Delicious!
I've been wondering... Whose cat is that?
ずっと気になってたんですけど
あの猫 何ですか？
Oh, he's just been hanging around here lately.
いつの間にか
住み着くようになって…
名前は “ちゃんこ”じゃ！
His name's Chanko!
You just made that up!
適当すぎんだろう
（佑真）ウワッ！
He likes you.
（蛍）好かれてますね
（桐仁）好かれてるな
So it seems.
フフッ…　ちゃんこ〜
Chanko!
（蛍）嫌われてますね
（桐仁）嫌われてるな
He doesn't like you.
So it seems.
Next Bout   “The Refreshing Sumo Wrestler, Sada Mizuki”